<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ireland | JPhenow]]></title>
  <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/categories/ireland/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jphenow.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T16:06:07-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jphenow.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jon Phenow]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ready-break: Here we come mainland]]></title>
    <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/ready-break-here-we-come-mainland/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/ready-break-here-we-come-mainland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our Study Abroad program was nice enough to not only take us across seas to Ireland, but also give us a week off to ourselves to check out Europe all by ourselves. Bobby Mandel and myself decided to get together and be travel buddies for this one, because we seem to have similar tastes, travel styles, and get along pretty well. Just before I wrote the last post (early October) we decided to look into where we could go for cheap that looks appetizing and nice to our wallets. We landed on a few different cities: Venice, Brussels (briefly), and Amsterdam. It was settled, we bought some Ryan air tickets, train tickets, and an Aer Lingus ticket and proceeded to seek out some accommodations for sleeping in each city. The date rolled along and we set sail on our journey.</p>

<p>We walked around Dublin for a night waiting for our plane, slept in a 7 Euro hostel, almost had our bags stolen while we slept (truly) and woke up by 3:30am to await our early flight to Venice. Several cups of coffee later our sketchy Ryan air flight took off and landed in Venice, where neither of us spoke the language, nor knew how to actually get onto the "island" of Venice. We followed some promising signs and were herded onto a bus that may or may not get us there. We did however dismount the bus to find a delightfully old, car-less floating (sort of) city with more canals than one can imagine. We found out the hostel we booked was across the larger canal so we decided to spend the day on the main part of Venice with our bags and just check out the city as much as possible before checking in. We saw as much as possible: San Marco, Da Vinci exhibits, naval exhibits, and just wandered and found little nooks and crannies of the city. We went to find our hostel and food before getting a good rest before another day of wandering. Today we wanted to see only a few more things (small city) and by about 12pm we decided we saw a lot of the things we liked on the map... so we proceeded to eat as much pizza and drink as much wine as we could for the remainder of the day. We ate and drank then walked around to find more random things, rinse and repeat. We had another early flight out to Brussels so we hit the hay by about 10pm.</p>

<p>We landed in Brussels airport and found the area quite pretty because it was in the middle of no where surrounded by almost nothing. We again took a bus into the City and quickly realized that all of Brussels was gray and gross. We promptly walked into the train station to get food and wait for a way into Amsterdam.</p>

<p>Arriving in Amsterdam from Brussels is like walking into a palace after spending years living in a box. The town is clean, gorgeously covered in red-brick buildings, extremely clean canals and some extremely delightful people. Our hostel was very friendly, we found a bar and hang out area in the basement and our room was towards the top of the thin building. Bobby and I forgot that we took the cheapest available bed which landed us in a full-size bed for both of us. We decided to cuddle instead of pay the extra 10 Euro a piece for our own beds. It was okay though because the Canadian sisters below us just made fun of us the entire time. Those same Canadian sisters actually became some good friends of ours. Us four split the making of a good soup and salad with some wine. They wanted to walk around town to see it at night and finally had some boys to take them (they thought it unsafe with just two girls). We walked around town, took some goofy pictures then headed back to the hostel. The morning after we all hung out we were parting ways so we made sure we could all find each other on Facebook and we went our separate paths.</p>

<p>We found, upon returning to the Park Lodge, that it had become our home. We plopped down on our beds and unpacked and felt like the traveling had ended, which in a way it had, but we realized that those cottages had become somewhere we wanted to return to, it was an odd feeling to realize this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland]]></title>
    <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/northern-ireland/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/northern-ireland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Northern Ireland is a different world, in my opinion, compared to the rest of Ireland. Northern Ireland, as some of you may know, is still part of the UK. There is constant argument, or more, between the Protestants (UK Unionists) and the Catholics (Irish). Without delving too far into the heart of Irish politics; the Catholics don't see themselves as British and the Protestants don't see themselves as part of Ireland at all.</p>

<p>We started our 4 night trip out in Derry (Londonderry for you Unionists). We had an entire hostel for two nights to just Johnnies and Bennies which made for some interesting nights. In Derry we visited the site where <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloody_Sunday_(1920)">Bloody Sunday</a> took place which was quite a moving experience. We explored the medieval town, had dinner at some of the rustic pubs in the area and took one of the best tours I've ever taken. Our walking tour guide was an older gentleman who was apparently an ex-taxi driver that everyone in the not-so-small city knew. He shared with us some of the very meaningful stories that centered around the murals one could see when walking down the Bloody Sunday Street. There were murals about the men involved directly with that Sunday, about men who went on hunger strike at different times, and some that were just about the life long search for peace. One mural could bring tears to even the hardest of people. One mural was painted to model picture of a girl standing in front of all the chaos looking rather lost. She died in the crossfire of the troubles that went on Derry in the late 20th Century. We've all heard of that kind of sad story but, this one is special, because this girl's dad never accepted her death so everyday from the day she died until his death he would sit across the street from the mural and talk to it as if she were sitting right in front of him. In respect of this man's loss no tour companies would allow tour groups to walk that far up the street, no one thought the tour was worth putting the man on display, and now they tell his story to keep the memories alive. Obviously this isn't the entirety of our travels through Derry, but this sticks out most to me.</p>

<p>Belfast was a different experience all together. Its a much more industrial town than anything we've seen before in Ireland. Going down certain streets you can still see Union Jack colors and designs painted in areas where you don't want to trot around telling people how Catholic you are. We stayed in an air-tight hostel who seemed relatively concerned about who came into the hostel doors. We found out later from our Belfast-born professor that they acted that way because he (a Catholic) still refuses to drive down the road we were on because there were many 'Unionist' activists known for parading around that street causing havoc. He was quite surprised we stayed there, luckily we didn't know how bad it was until we told him where we were. Our tour of Belfast was yet another new experience. Many of us, throughout or learnings in History class, have come to have something of dislike for British, or at least we can tell when someone is being biased. Some of us picked up that our tour guide was extremely Unionist as she bashed all that the Nationalists stood for. We did learn, though, as we went down the 'peace' wall and up and down the Falls and Shankhill roads. It was amazing to see how a modern community can still be so literally separated.</p>

<p>As I said after writing about Derry, there's probably more to be said about our travels - the Bushmills brewery, the count of pints we drank, the fun people we met who play dance with old Irish music, but it seemed more appropriate to talk about the things someone might not expect to find in each area of Ireland.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dublin]]></title>
    <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/dublin/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/dublin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By the time we begin to set sail for Dublin many of us are realizing how much time we <em>don't</em> have left in Ireland and at the Park Lodge with our Irish Friends. Everyone is looking to enjoy things to the fullest again. In Dublin some of us have a great time connecting our latest History learning to the monuments and buildings across the city. We went into the General Post Office that was shot up in the early 20th Century, saw a replica famine ship, and many other things.</p>

<p>Our first night there we were set loose to find our own food then had to be dressed up for a showing of Ibsen's "John Gabriel Borkman" at the Abbey theater. This was an experience to say the least. The set was absolutely gorgeous, and the acting was wonderful. John Borkman was played by Alan Rickman who expertly commanded everyone's attention.</p>

<p>As I said, everyone in the group was trying to live to the fullest in this trip so we spent each night seeking live music and full pints. We succeeded each night in remembering how we fell in love with the country of Ireland.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A grand time was had by all]]></title>
    <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/a-grand-time-was-had-by-all/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/12/20/a-grand-time-was-had-by-all</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time is slipping away from us as we can see the end near.</p>

<p>The Ireland group spent an afternoon down by the soccer fields playing some intense wet-ground football. We had a fantastic Thanksgiving meal and night in the pub with those at Park Lodge who make this all possible. We even had our bus driver and one of our professors join us for dinner, a talent show of the students, and some pints at the pub.</p>

<p>The weekend before our last week many of us spend the entire time in Galway at pubs, shopping, walking, and just remembering. We had some great nights hanging out with each other and sharing stories from what seems like so long ago and yet not long ago at all.</p>

<p>Everyone spent time preparing for final exams and essays.</p>

<p>In Theology we talked about Christmas tradition for some time then we sat around in the pub singing familiar Christmas carols to each other - we'll miss you Mary Clancy. She never talked long enough about one thing for us to learn anything, the class structure was not there, and we still don't know what you were trying to teach us, but you were the sweetest Irishwoman we know and we won't forget your kindness and love for Johnnies and Bennies.</p>

<p>Our final day in History was spent praying we could pass the large exam. Laurence Marley, the man who knows it all about all things historical or otherwise. The man with a plan and a story for everything. Easily one of the most impressive professors I've ever had the pleasure to learn from.</p>

<p>Gerard O'Brien, the Irish James Bond of Literature. The suavest, and coolest man you've ever hoped to share a brandy with. Another class we're not sure what we learned about, but we loved to hear you reminisce about Irish poetry and non-sensical writings of Joyce or some other great classic writer.</p>

<p>Our directors Elizabeth Stoltz and Dave All-that-is-man Hutcheson taught us that you don't have to know what's going on or how much money you have to run a study abroad program. They were like grandparents to us all and though we all may have different problems with them, they were some of the most caring and generous people we could have had the pleasure to be our directors. Elizabeth Stoltz's Guiness cake and Dave Hutcheson's run will always be memories I hold close to my heart.</p>

<p>Finally JP, the man who can "fix" anything as long as it involves liquor or a pint. We'll miss the man who took care of us through many nights and had a watchful eye like a good uncle and close friend.</p>

<p>Our final night we had a large bonfire on the rocks, thanks to Evan Howard who decided to rebuild a 10-year-old pit built by Johnnies of old. Whiskey, beer, and stories were shared with some attempts at singing. We proceeded to a final night in High Hughes' in Spiddal, one last drunchie stop at Super Mac's and back to the Park Lodge. We were allowed by JP to crash the last Irish wedding before people started to head home. We danced, we drank, we picked Nate up off the floor.</p>

<p>I didn't sleep that night as I packed showered and remembered the first day I walked into the cottage. Its hard to believe it ended, but life goes on and there will be more memories to be had throughout life. I'll miss the nights we had and look forward to meeting up with life long friends made throughout the time I had in Ireland.</p>

<p>Indeed, a grand time was had by all.</p>

<p>Cottage 5 (and 6 I spose) for life. Many a reunion will be had.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southern Ireland]]></title>
    <link href="http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/10/01/southern-ireland/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jphenow.com/blog/2010/10/01/southern-ireland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 15th: wake up, finish packing, hit the road by 10am. We stuffed in our new home for the next four days, a stuffy Lally's Tour bus, and drove for an hour or so to stop at W. B. Yeats' old Cottage/Tower. We met Gerard O'Brien, our literature professor, at the Cottage/Tower; he told us some more about the old structure and read a poem and we headed to Coole Park. Coole Park is where the famous Lady Gregory lived for years. Here we checked out the lake, grounds, and autograph tree. We moved on and quickly came to the realization that it was 3pm and none of us have eaten so we found refuge at a SuperMac's (the McDonald's Equivalent of Ireland) and continued our trek to Cork. Once in Cork we toured the beautiful city and it's university. Finally we got to our first hostel of the trip, which was again more packed and stuffy so many of us simply dropped our stuff off and went to find a pub and/or some food. In this town we found a pub called "The Franciscan Well," which turned out to be a great microbrewery for us to hang out in that night. This pub also had us stumble upon 3 fellow Minnesotans! One guy recognized a Twins hat someone had on and we talked to them for some time, but, oddly, the conversation was coming to a close shortly after we found out two of them had close relatives on the Tommie football team. "Enough of this company," I said. I didn't actually say that but, their relatives are on the Tommie team, one of them a current stud on the team.</p>

<p>We moved on in the morning to Blarney Castle and did, indeed, kiss the Blarney stone. So yes I am much more eloquent at this point, can you tell? Later, we stopped on the side of the road to have a look at the Michael Collins Memorial, where he was assassinated, and one of our directors gave us the full story. To this day, you can see many passers-by making the sign of the cross as they continue driving. We traveled a little further to stop at Muckross Castle and have a look around. We finally stopped in Killarney and dropped our stuff in a new hostel and went to find groceries that we could cook in the community kitchen of the hostel. Off we go again into town, since its someone's birthday, and we found a few great pubs to hang out in. Met a man from Wisconsin this time, who was probably 7 feet tall.</p>

<p>This next day we spent at Muckross house and driving for several hours around the Ring of Kerry, which is just a pretty peninsula with lots of cliffs and great views of the ocean. We saw the island that is the closest European point to the US. That was mostly a long day in a bus, but we eventually returned to our same hostel as the previous night and had a more relaxed night in the pubs; we actually found an old fashioned Irish storyteller, who was the most vulgar person I've ever met in my life.</p>

<p>This day was much easier. We had a short drive to Tralee where we checked out the Kerry County Museum then drove through the Dingle Peninsula for a few hours, which was similar to the sights seen in the Ring of Kerry. We landed again in Tralee and, again, dropped our stuff and went searching for groceries to cook in the community kitchen. Found a few more pubs and had a quiet night.</p>

<p>The final day had arrived of our exhausting trip and we were all ready for a break. We hopped on the bus and went to the Cliffs of Moher for a few hours. We ate, looked at the exhibit and walked around the "regular" parts of the cliffs, which were all covered with big stone fences, stopping you from getting with 20ft of the edge. Well if you went all the way to the left end of the fences there was an interesting sight; first there was a memorial for "those lost at the cliffs", then there was a "DANGER DO NOT GO BEYOND THIS POINT" sign, next there was sign saying how windy and dangerous the cliffs were, finally you could see all the people who disregarded all of these signs and warnings of death. Well we, being the smart deliberators we all are, followed suit and walked past these signs to get the real views of the cliffs. We took some silly pictures of us pretending to fall and be more scared than we were, in reality and we quickly scurried back to safety. I encourage you to look at <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/j.phenow/Galway10#">http://picasaweb.google.com/j.phenow/Galway10#</a> so you can see the fun pictures. There are probably some other good ones taken by others on Facebook. We ended our day with a stop in Galway for some weekly groceries and rest.</p>

<p>An interesting few days, indeed. Hope all is well with everyone at home, see you guys in a few months! Its coming up fast!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
